Okay, let's start off this lesson by first
حسنا، دعونا نبدأ هذا الدرس أولا
making the important distinction between savings and investment.
جعل التمييز المهم بين الادخار والاستثمار.
Two terms which are often and wrongly used interchangeably.
مصطلحان غالبا ما يتم استخدامهما بشكل خاطئ بالتبادل.
So here's the important distinction.
لذا إليك الفرق المهم.
When your goal is simply to save money,
عندما يكون هدفك هو توفير المال ببساطة،
your primary goal is to protect that money from any loss.
هدفك الأساسي هو حماية هذا المال من أي خسارة.
So when you save, you either put your money in a vault or
لذلك عند الادخار، إما أن تضع أموالك في قبو أو
into very safe investment vehicles like a money market or
في سيارات استثمار آمنة جدا مثل سوق المال أو
the government bonds of a relatively safe country like the United States or Canada.
السندات الحكومية في بلد آمن نسبيا مثل الولايات المتحدة أو كندا.
In contrast, when you invest your money you are willing to take on more risk.
في المقابل، عندما تستثمر أموالك فأنت على استعداد لتحمل المزيد من المخاطر.
Precisely because you are trying to gain a higher return or reward.
على وجه التحديد لأنك تحاول الحصول على عائد أعلى أو مكافأة.
So you might invest your money in any number of vehicles that range from
لذلك قد تستثمر أموالك في أي عدد من المركبات التي تتراوح بين
stocks and real estate, to precious metals like gold and silver, and
الأسهم والعقارات، والمعادن الثمينة مثل الذهب والفضة،
precious objects like fine art and classic cars.
والأشياء الثمينة مثل الفنون الجميلة والسيارات الكلاسيكية.
And that leads us to the first big concept we have to wrap our heads around.
وهذا يقودنا إلى أول مفهوم كبير علينا أن نلف رؤوسنا حولها.
Basically, the idea of the risk/reward ratio.
في الأساس، فكرة نسبة المخاطر/المكافأة.
As a practical matter, the more risk you are willing to take on as an investor,
وكمسألة عملية، كلما زادت المخاطر التي ترغب في اتخاذها كمستثمر،
the higher your reward or return on that investment should be.
كلما زادت مكافأتك أو عائد على هذا الاستثمار.
That's because the ultimate risk of an investment is that you will lose some or
وذلك لأن الخطر النهائي للاستثمار هو أنك سوف تفقد بعض أو
all of your investment capital if things go wrong.
كل رأس المال الاستثماري الخاص بك إذا ساءت الأمور.
So, for example, it's a lot riskier to invest in corporate bonds than
لذلك، على سبيل المثال، الاستثمار في سندات الشركات أكثر خطورة من
government bonds, so corporate bonds usually offer a high rate of interest.
السندات الحكومية، لذلك عادة ما توفر سندات الشركات نسبة فائدة عالية.
Hey, if they didn't, investors wouldn't buy them.
مهلا، إذا لم يفعلوا، المستثمرين لن يشتروها.
They'd buy the safe government bonds instead.
كانوا يشترون السندات الحكومية الآمنة بدلا من ذلك.
Similarly, it's a lot riskier to invest in brand new technology stocks than
وبالمثل، فإن الاستثمار في أسهم التكنولوجيا الجديدة من
established blue chip stocks like Proctor and Gamble and General Electric.
أسهم الرقاقات الزرقاء الثابتة مثل بروكتور وغامبل وجنرال إلكتريك أكثر خطورة.
So generally, investors expect a higher rate of return on these riskier stocks.
بشكل عام، يتوقع المستثمرون معدل عائد أعلى على هذه الأسهم الأكثر خطورة.
As for the various risks you face, when you invest in instruments like stocks,
أما بالنسبة للمخاطر المختلفة التي تواجهها، فعندما تستثمر في أدوات مثل الأسهم
real estate, gold or even impressionist paintings, these risks come in many forms.
والعقارات والذهب أو حتى اللوحات الانطباعية، فإن هذه المخاطر تأتي في أشكال عديدة.
For example, you might buy a house hoping to flip it for
على سبيل المثال، قد تشتري منزلاً على أمل قلبه لتحقيق
a quick profit and wind up seeing housing prices suddenly plunge.
ربح سريع وينتهي الأمر برؤية أسعار المساكن تغرق فجأة.
That's how the whole 2007 financial crisis started, and it wasn't pretty.
هكذا بدأت الأزمة المالية لعام 2007 كلها، ولم تكن جميلة.
Or you may decide to become a gold bug.
أو قد تقرر أن تصبح علة الذهب.
I don't recommend that, and
أنا لا أوصي بذلك،
invest your money in gold bars or any one of a number of stock market trading
واستثمار أموالك في سبائك الذهب أو أي واحد من عدد من
instruments that allow you to essentially bet on the price of gold going higher.
أدوات التداول في سوق الأسهم التي تسمح لك أساسا الرهان على سعر الذهب يذهب أعلى.
However, if after you make your gold investment, the economy goes
ومع ذلك، إذا بعد إجراء استثمارك في الذهب، فإن الاقتصاد
into a downturn and the rate of inflation falls along with the industrial demand for
يذهب إلى الانكماش وانخفاض معدل التضخم جنبا إلى جنب مع الطلب الصناعي على
gold, you may suddenly find that the $20,000 you dropped on the gold market
الذهب، قد تجد فجأة أن 20،000 دولار الذي أسقطته في سوق الذهب
may only be worth half that.
قد يكون فقط يساوي نصف ذلك.
So, the big point here, is that whatever you invest in,
لذا، النقطة المهمة هنا، هي أنه مهما كنت تستثمر في،
it's important not just the return or reward being offered but
فمن المهم ليس فقط العائد أو المكافأة التي يتم تقديمها ولكن
also the risks involved in making that particular investment.
أيضا المخاطر التي ينطوي عليها صنع هذا الاستثمار بالذات.
And now hear this, if the reward or
والآن نسمع هذا، إذا كانت المكافأة أو
return being offered to you sounds too good to be true, it probably is.
العودة المقدمة لك تبدو جيدة جدا ليكون صحيحا، فمن المحتمل أن يكون كذلك.
So don't get sucked into any fly by night investments.
لذلك لا تحصل على امتص في أي ذبابة عن طريق الاستثمارات ليلا.
Whenever you might be tempted, remember this axioms from the great philosopher,
كلما كنت قد يميل، تذكر هذه البديهيات من الفيلسوف العظيم،
WC Fields, never give a sucker an even break, and you can't cheat an honest man.
WC Fields، لا تعطي مصاصة حتى استراحة، ولا يمكنك خداع رجل صادق.
>> Sir you impugn my honor.
>> سيدي أنت تحسب شرفي.
As my dear old grandfather Lipbock said just before the sprung the trap,
كما قال جدي العزيز ليبوك قبل ظهور الفخ
he said you can't cheat an honest man.
قال أنه لا يمكنك خداع رجل صادق
Never give a sucker an even break or
أبدا إعطاء مصاصة استراحة حتى أو
smarten up a chump >> Okay,
أذكى حتى أحمق >> حسنا,
enough about the risk reward ratio.
بما فيه الكفاية عن نسبة مكافأة المخاطر.
When you're ready, let's move on to Part 2 of the lecture to examine the concept of
عندما تكون مستعدًا، دعنا ننتقل إلى الجزء الثاني من المحاضرة لفحص
rate of return, a really cool financial tool known as diversification.
مفهوم معدل العائد، وهو أداة مالية رائعة تعرف باسم التنويع.
[MUSIC]
[ موسيقى]